Guide to the Education Sun RG.39.201
New York University Archives
Education Sun
1931-1955
New York University Archives
RG.39.201
12 Linear Feet in 10 boxes
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Education Sun, dating from 1931 to 1955. The paper was published by NYU School of Education students (later known as the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development), and documented campus life, local and national news, athletics, and other student activities. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collections includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Education Sun, dating from 1931 to 1955. The paper was published by NYU School of Education students (later known as the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development), and documented campus life, local and national news, athletics, and other student activities. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collections includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies.
Historical Note
New York University has had many student newspapers since its founding. The Education Sun was the student newspaper for the NYU School of Education (later known as the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development) from 1931 through 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
College student newspapers and periodicals.; Student activities.; New York University. School of Education
- Microfilm copies
  - Education Sun, October 1931-May 1938 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5070)
  - Education Sun, September 1938-August 1944 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5071)
  - Education Sun, September 1944-August 1949 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5072)
  - Education Sun, September 1949-July 1954 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5073)
  - Education Sun, September 1954-August 1955 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5074)
- Bound copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Education Sun, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Education Sun, 1933-1934 (Box 2)
  - Education Sun, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Education Sun, 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Education Sun, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Education Sun, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Box 6, Box 7)
  - Education Sun, 1952-1955 (Box 8)
- Loose print copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Education Sun, 1932-1939 (Box 9)
  - Education Sun, 1941-1950 (Box 10)